In this demo, I'm going to show you an example of an Ingress Controller.
First let me show you how to Ingress Controller works.
I'm going to use nginx Ingress Controller, which is an existing one.
This is a Replication Controller.
So, if this one would crash, it would be automatically relaunched.
It's called "nginx-ingress-controller" and it's an image that comes from a Google container.
It's a "nginx-ingress-controller" and it's this version here. It's going to check the health.
We have a "readinessProbe" to know when the container is ready to be deployed.
And there is the "livenessProbe" to periodically check whether our container is still healthy.
We are going to specify a pod name, which is our pod name and the namespace, which is "default" in our case, unless
you specify another namespace. Don't run this on port 80 and port 443.
This Ingress Controller is really working on the standard HTTP port and the HTTPS port. It is going to give these as arguments
when it's going to launch the container.
So, this the Ingress Controller that you could write yourself even if you want,
but we are going to use one that already exists.
We are also going to say, at the "default-backend-service" is the "echoheaders-default".
And this is a service that I'm going to launch.
Traffic will be forwarded to this service, when there is no match, so I'm going to say, "these hosts",
I am going to say in my Ingress rules,
these are the hosts, "helloworld-v1.example.com", "helloworld-v2.example.com"
If those don't match then go to this default service.
Let me just, "kubectl create" the Ingress.
The object controller, the echo-service, the "helloworld-v1"
and the "helloworld-v2"
So, these are just services that we can access.
This is our "helloworld-v1" app
and this is our "helloworld-v2" app.
And the only thing that is different between those two is that I am asking for image version 2,
and one is just asking for the standard image.
Let me check if the pods are up. Yes, they are running now.
Let me get the IP address.
"minikube ip", which is just going to give me the IP address of my cluster.
If you're testing is on AWS you have the IP addresses in s2 console, you just might have to change
your security groups to make sure those ports are open.
I'm going to "curl" this IP address.
What's going to happen then,
I'm not specifying any hosts.
Those are non-existent hosts, so I cannot just go in my browser and type them in,
because they actually don't exist.
You could use real world host and you can just use your browser.
I'm just going to give an argument to fake that I'm sending that I'm using those hosts.
I don't specify any hosts so I'm going to hit this default backend service, "echoheaders-default"
and this is just going to give me the HTTP headers.
So, "curl" I'm hitting this default service now.
Let me now pass the header and let me pass the host, and the host is going to be
"helloworld-v1.example.com"
This "curl" command has the same effect as going to a real DNS browser.
This gives us the "Hello World!".
So, our Ingress Controller for us now to my "helloworld-v1" on deployments.
Let's now try v2.
And what do I get? I'll show it.
"Hello world v2!" here.
Do you what do I get?
"Hello world v2!"
Now, our Ingress Controller forwarded us to "Hello world v2!" to my to my second "helloworld".
And I'm pointing out to the pods that actually I should point towards the services.
So, this is the default one, and this is if we hit "v1" and, this is if we hit "v2", this is just the one from the previous lab.
Don't worry about that one.
So, that's how the Ingress Controller works, we basically have the capability.
It's still in beta now, but it will become stable.
We have the capability to just run a load balancer inside our cluster that is going to redirect traffic
to the correct host for us, which is a viable alternative if you don't want to run an ELB, or an external
AWS from your cloud provider, because those also cost money and don't have all the capabilities that
you may be need. Because when you write your own controller you could add all of all you wanted,
like Enterprise Authentication if necessary.