In this demo, I'm going to show you how to start using volumes.
I'm going to use my kops cluster again.
So, I logged in again in my vagrant xenial box. And first you will need to create a volume on AWS.
And if you're working with kops, then you must have set up the AWS too, because it was one of the prerequisites.
So, I'm going to use the AWS to create a volume.
I'm going to use "aws ec2" to create volume.
I'm going to create a volume of size 10, in "eu-west-1a". It's going to be general purpose 2 which is just an EBS volume.
Make sure that you create your volume in the same zone that your Kubernetes cluster is open up,
otherwise it's not going to work.
This is the volume ID that you need to select, you are going to replace this.
And I'm going to insert this into my "helloworld" with a volume.
So, I'm going to replace, I'm going to use this volume ID,
I'm going to put it right here,
"volumeID" and then this volume ID. And this volume ID is going to be attached to the node that this pod is going to run on.
And it could be mounted under "/myvol". Let me first check whether my nodes are running.
I have three nodes running and then I am going to launch this deployment "helloworld-deployment" created.
"Kubectl get pod", container is creating.
It's pulling the image and now the container is created.
You have a volume here, "myvolume" which is a persistent disk resource in AWS,
"AWSElasticBlockStorage" with a volume ID. So, I should now be able to execute something in this pod.
Let me just start "bash" and I have volume "myvol".
Let me just write something in "myvol", just to see how it works.
I'm going to write "test" in "myvol".
"/myvol/myvol.txt"
I'm also going to write "test2" in "/test.txt"
We have two files, "myvol.txt", "test.txt".
And just think about what is going to happen if this pod crashes, because we wrote something in "/",
we wrote something in the volume. When our pod goes,
well if the node goes, then the pod needs to be rescheduled.
So this pod is running on the node with this IP address.
So, if you want to test what would happen, if the node would be rescheduled, we could drain a node, which means, we prepare a node to go offline.
"kubectl drain", and then the node, and then it's going to start draining the nodes, we are going to use "--force" here.
So that the pod is for sure killed. Then I'm going to do "kubectl get pod".
And already a new pod is being created.
If I describe this one. "Kubectl describe pod", and then the new pod, then you can see that this pod is now attached to another instance.
You just have to wait a little bit till the warnings go away.
And now the volume is attached to this new node.
So, what happened is that this volume detached from the old node and now is reattached to the new node.
So, our container has been recreated, but it is still using the same volume.
So, let me login again, let me open a shell on our new pod.
And, if I take a look in "myvol", I will see that I still have have "myvol.txt", but of course,
because this is a new container, I don't have those "test.txt" anymore,
because "test.txt" was not saved in the volume, in the container itself,
and when the pod gets rescheduled, all the information that has been written on the container disappears.
So, when you have a stateful application that needs to write something, then you always need to to use volumes,
because then your data will be kept even if the node crashes, or even if the node needs to be rescheduled.
And this can happen all the time.
Stateful applications you can only use with volumes, or some other mechanism, to save the data not inside the container itself, but using a volume or external services.
In lectures, I will show you how Kubernetes can ultimately create those volumes for you.
When you're finished, make sure that you remove this volume again.
So, this volume needs to be deleted.
"aws ec2 delete-volume" with "--volume-id" and then, the volume id.
Of course when it is not attached anymore.
So, you can only do that when it's detached.
So, first you can you need to remove your pod, and if you wait some time, you will be able to detach it.