In this lecture, I'll be talking about Pet Sets. Stateful distributed apps on a Kubernetes cluster.
Pet Sets is a new feature starting from Kubernetes 1.3. It is introduced to be able to run stateful applications
that need a stable pod hostname, instead of a podname-randomstring
But, if you used up till now, whenever we used the deployment or replica set,
then there was some degree of randomness in our pod name.
Your name will have an index, when having multiple instances of a pod, instead of that random string.
For instance, "podname-0", "podname-1", and "podname-2".
Another reason why you would Pet Sets is when you have a stateful app
that requires multiple pods with a volume's based on their ordinal number, which means, "podname-" and then a number,
or the needs a static hostname.
Also know that when you use Pet Sets, currently deleting and/or scaling a PetSet down
will not delete the volumes associated with the PetSet.
They want to make sure that when you use Pet Sets the volumes are not just deleted.
So what does it mean?
A pet set will allow your stateful app to use DNS to find other peers.
For instance, this can be useful for Cassandra clusters, ElasticSearch clusters, that use DNS to find
other members in the cluster.
One running node of your PetSet app is called a Pet, which is one node in a guest on a cluster.
Using Pet Sets you can run, for instance, five Cassandra nodes, own Kubernetes named cassandra-0 until cassandra-5.
And those can then discover each other, because those are peers based on this static hostname in the
pod. If you wouldn't use Pet Sets, you would get the dynamic hostname, which you wouldn't be able to use in
your configuration files as the name of your pod always change.
So, the big difference here is that you don't really want to just connect to a service and then you're going to get any pod,
you want to make sure that, for instance, "cassandra-1" connects to "cassandra-5",
and to make that work, Pet Sets.
Because only with Pet Sets you have these static hosting of your pod.
So you know the hostname of the order to connect to.
A Pet Set will also allow your stateful app to order
your startup and teardown of the Pets, instead of randomly terminating Pets, which is one instance of
your app, you will know which one that will go.
This is useful, if you first need to drain the data from a node before you can shut it down.
If you're using Cassandra, you will know what this means.
If you want to shut down one node in your cluster, you first need to stop sending data to it.
There's still a lot of future work that needs to be done for Pet Sets.
Pet Sets are currently still in alpha,
I'll add a demo when becomes more stable.
So, there might be still things that are going to change. Whenever it becomes more stable
I'll add them to this course.