Welcome to the Kubernetes course.
Let me first introduce myself.
My name is Edward Viaene and I'm a consultant and trainer in Cloud and Big Data technologies.
I'm a big advocate of Agile and DevOps techniques in all the projects I work on.
I held various roles from banking to startups.
I have a background in Unix/Linux, Networks, Security, Risk and distributed computing. Nowadays.
I specialize in everything that has to do with the cloud and the host. I give.
all online training on Udemy. I do the host, district computing, Cloud and DevOps. I give online training on Udemy. I do DevOps, Distributed Computing, Cloud, Terraform, and Big Data training using online video
lectures just like this one.
I have more than 7000 enrolled students in more than 100 countries.
This is what the course is going to be about.
I will first start with what is Kubernetes? I will show you how to set up a cluster and how to build
your first container.
Then I will teach you the Kubernetes basics.
It will be about deployments, pods, labels, healthchecks and so on.
Then I have a section on advanced topics.
Those include some more advanced things that you can do with Kubernetes.
And then there's a full section on the administration.
You need to know how the Kubernetes cluster works and
You need to be able to administer it. Once you have more people using the cluster,
it can become more challenging.
So what are the course objectives? To be able to understand, to be able to deploy and use Kubernetes
To get started with containerization and to run those containers on Kubernetes. To use Kubernetes as a single note and on AWS. To be able to run stateless and stateful applications on Kubernetes and
to be able to administer your Kubernetes cluster.