So what to do when you've finished this course.
I have some other courses that might interest you.
You can find all my courses at url that is displayed here.
The other course I have it might interest you is the "Advanced Kubernetes Course". I've launched the "Advanced Kubernetes Course"
in October 2017 and I'll just show you what it covers.
It builds upon this Kubernetes course.
So, I assume that you did every lecture of this course and then we get started with centralized
logging, using elastic search, Fluentd, Kibana, and LogTrail.
I didn't cover Authentication using open ID, Authorization using RBAC, Packaging using Helme, the Job
Resource, Scaling, Deploying on Kubernetes using Spinnaker, Microservices on Kubernetes using Linkerd,
Federation, and Monitoring. And can get this course at this url with this coupon code:
BONUS_DEVOPS
And here is a list of my other courses that might interest you.
You can all take them with the same coupon code.