In this demo, I will show you how to do local Kubernetes set up using minikube.
The first step is to go to "http://github.com/kubernetes/minikube".
Here, you have the minikube repository to run Kubernetes locally.
So, What's minikube?
That's what I already explained in previous lecture.
Here, you have the link to the latest release, so if you click on latest release,
then you're going to go to the release page, and the latest release at this time is v0.12.2.
There are probably be already a new release, when you look at this page, but the installation instructions
shouldn't really change much.
I have OSX.
So, I'm just going to copy paste this comment.
If you are Linux you can use this command.
If you are windows you can download the "minikube-windows.exe".
If you're a Windows you still need to rename it to "minikube.exe".
And you need to add it to your path.
The easiest way is to just save it, so the easiest way is to just save it into a directory, and then "CD"
to the path, and you can execute "minikube.exe". If you want some more information about the Windows installation minikube,
just have a look at the procedure document where you can find extra information.
I'm using Mac, so I will just execute this command.
I opened a terminal on my Mac.
If you don't know how, you just do "command+space" and you type terminal, enter. And then, you see something like this.
Copy and paste command. It will then download approximately 80 megabytes.
Once the download is complete, it will ask you to enter your Mac OS password,
or on linux, your root password, because we are moving, because we are moving this minikube to user a local bin.
So, I just ended my password, and minikube is now available. So, I can started with minikube start.
So, I am starting a local Kubernetes cluster.
This might take some time, because it needs to boot up the virtual machine. So, this now set up our Kubernetes cluster,
and it says "kubectl" is not configured to use the cluster. It actually has configured--
This "config" is now created. So, that "kubectl" can connect to our newly created vm with Kubernetes.
If you don't have the "kubectl" tool yet, have a look at my procedure document, and there's a link for Linux, Mac, and Windows platforms.
So, I'm on the Mac platform.
So, I will just download this one.
This is again a 63 megabytes binary.
And, this is the command find tool.
You need to download this command line tool first, and then you'll be able to use "kubectl".
And, you don't need to do any confirmation anymore, because minikube did this configuration for us.
"Kubectl" will take a look at this "~/.kube/config" and will then know that it needs to go to this
IP address and this port to connect to the cluster. "Kubectl" is downloaded.
So, we are going to do the same thing as we did with minikube, we are going to give it execution permissions,
and we are going to move it to "/usr/local/bin" together with minikube. Then, we can execute "kubectl".
So, if you just press enter, you see all the comments available.
So, "kubectl" is working.
So, lets try a few commands, just to see if our cluster is working.
First, let's run "kubectl" with the command "run".
Run means, run a particular image on the cluster, the name of we going to give this is "hello-minikube".
And, the image is going to come from Google and just called echo server.
So, for a simple app, we going to put it on port 88, just press enter.
It's says, "deployment 'hello-minikube' created".
And then, I'm going to use the command "kubectl expose  deployment hello-minikube --type=NodePort".
So, this is going to expose this port to our host machine, to our clients, to where I'm typing.
Don't worry if you don't understand these commands in detail yet, because I'll be explaining them later in the course.
We just want to know what a cluster is we're not, so I am going to press enter.
"service 'hello-minikube' exposed"
And what I want to know is the URL. You see, "minikube service hello-minikube --url"
And this can take some time, because it needs to download this image, this echo server, and this image
can already be quite big, because every time you are pulling an image it's a fully contained image,
so it includes already operating system,
it includes all the dependencies with this echo server.
It took longer than expected,
but here I have the URL of the service that is not exposed to my host machine, which means I can just
use my regular browser to access this URL.
The reason why it takes so long, it is because of the download.
Right now, I'm on a slow connection.
So, if you also have a slow connection, you will see exactly the same thing.
It takes some time to download this image.
So, let's go to the browser and here you can see this is an echo service.
It just shows some things.
So, you can do "Test123", then you will see the real path for the "Test123".
So, our cluster is working.
We can schedule containers on Kubenetes.
And it just pulled a container for us with this application on.
So, this is it for this lecture.
If you want to close your cluster again, if you want to stop your cluster again, you can just type, "minikube stop"
And then, it will break down your minikube cluster.
So, this is it for this lecture, in a next one hour show it to do exactly the same thing on AWS.
So, if you don't want to use minikube, you don't want to use your own PC, you can use Amazon AWS, I will show you how to do that.
If you don't want to run it on the AWS, so you can skip that lecture, and go straight to the one after that.