So, you can go to "http://github.com/kubernetes/kops" here there is download the latest release,
and you can download the "kops-linux-amd64", copy link address, and then I can download this "kops-linux-amd64" on this machine.
This download, I can "chmod +x kops-linux-amd64", plus executable flag.
So they can execute it and I can move this to "/usr/local/bin/kops-linux-amd64"
I have to use a "Sudo". And then, I'm going to download "python-pip", because "python-pip" will allow me install "awscli".
The "awscli" I will also need before I set up this cluster on AWS.
So, this is installed, I should be able to do "pip install awscli"
And this should give me the command of hight utility, called aws that I will be able to use.
So, now I type "aws". I can now execute commands with AWS.
If you don't have an aws account yet, open one, "http://aws.amazon.com", create an AWS account, and when you create your account you will automatically get the free tiar.
Once you open your aws account, you will see a screen like this.
These are all the servers that you can use in aws.
You need to go to "Identity and Access Management", because we are going to create a user first, so that kops can deploy Kubernetes.
So, "Identity and Access Management".
You go to "Users", "Create New User", call it "kops", and you are going to generate an access key for this user.
These are the access that you need to configure aws on your new machine.
So, remember you just installed it aws command utility.
What we're going to do now is, we go into the shell of our VM, where we installed aws command utility.
I am going to type, "aws configure" it will open your access key and for the aws, "Secret" access key,
both are printed when you were creating this user.
You can specify default region or add an input format, but that's not necessary. So, that's it.
Now what the aws utility did actually created these files in the AWS.
Our credentials are now configured, so we can now use AWS.
One more thing we need to do, is we need to give our user, our kops user we just created permissions.
we should give it administrator permissions, so we close this.
Go to our new user, and we're going to attach a policy,
and we are going to give it administrator access.
You click, attach policy.
And now our kops user has administrator access. You could also give less permission to kops, but then you have to do it manually.
So, the easiest way is to give the administrator access, if you're concerned about giving too much access
to your kops user, you can always change it into only what it needs.
Next, I'm going to go back to the welcome screen, and I'm going to go to "S3".
"S3" is an object store, you can compare it with Google Drive, or a drop box, and you're going to create a new bucket,
and this bucket is going to be used for kops state.
And I am just going to add some random string at the end, which you also should do, and you also should make it random.
Because this bucket named needs to be unique in Amazon, in that region this region.
This region that you specified here going to be the region where you want to deploy your cluster.
So, if you want to deploy cluster in Ireland, you should choose the Ireland region.
So, depending on where you are, you can choose a different bucket. If you don't know what region to choose,
there's a tool "CloudPing.info", http thing. For me, Europe and Frankfurt are the closest ones.
I am going to go with Ireland. You are going to do this from different locations, so you're going to see different results.
I am going to choose Ireland, I am going to click "Create", and now I have my kops bucket.
Next is the DNS, so kops is also going to set the DNS for us,
but first we need to set up a domain for that, a subdomain, so you can use route 53 for that.
Route 53 allows you to do DNS management.
kops expect you to enter a subdomain, and kops will manage a subdomain for you,
but you already need to create this zone in route 53 so that kops can manage it for you.
You can either register a new domain name here on Amazon or even somewhere cheaper, you can get some for a couple of bucks.
There are also free solutions, so you don't need to spend money for a domain name.
There is a ".dk" and there is also a provider to give you subdomains that you can use in Route 53,
so you don't need to spend money if you don't want.
If you don't have a domain name, it's probably the easiest way to just go for something free.
Have a look at the procedure documents, I listed some free solutions there.
I have my own domain name, so I'm going to get started here with DNS management.
I'm going to create a hosted zone.
Even if you have your own domain name, or if you opt for one of the free solutions, you still need to create this hosted zone.
And this is actually going to cost you some money right now just cost you a half a dollar per month to create that zone.
So, if you don't want to spend any money at all, you might just want to run minikube, maybe kops is not the solution for you.
So, I'm going to click "Create Hosted Zone" and I am going to use "kubernetes.newtech.academy".
I have a domain in "newtech.academy".
So, what I will do is, I will make sure that, "kubernetes.newtech.academy" is going to forward to Route 53.
And, to make it forward, I need to specify these values here.
And those are going to be different for you as name servers for this subdomain.
My domain is hosted at "namecheap", so I have to go to "namecheap",
tell "namecheap" that "kubernet.newtech.academy" is hosted by Route 53,
and these are the name servers.
You'll easily find that, if you buying a domain, it's quite straightforward to make those changes.
Just to show you how it works with "namedcheap".
You have something called Advanced DNS,
and here I added four new records for Kubernetes, for these domain names, so that I have ""kubernet.newtech.academy" and  they point to the Route 53 name servers.
So, I did at "New record", "NS Records", Kubernetes as a "Host", and whatever "Name Server" that you will see.
So, if you do this yourself, don't take these names services, but that ones that you see when you add a record in Amazon.
If you use something else, that "namecheap", for instance, a free ".dk" name,
this will look a little bit different, but it's the same principle.
You will have add an "NS Record" for a domain, or a subdomain, to be able to make this work.
Once we set up the DNS, kops is going to manage the DNS for us using route 53.
So, now we have done all the preparation and we can finally start launching our cluster using kops.
And that I will show you in the next demo.