At this point, you should have set up your Vagrant Box, you should have set up your AWS.
So, now we can launch our Kubernetes cluster using kops here and logged in to my "ubuntu-xenial" box.
Before setting up the cluster, you need to make sure that you have kubectl installed as well.
This URL you can find in the procedure document, you can just download it.
You move it to use a local bin, exactly where kops is as well, and you give it execution permissions.
And then, when you type "kubectl", you have "kubectl"  available.
Before creating the cluster, you will also have to create new ssh keys, and those ssh keys will be used to log in to the cluster.
"ssh-keygen" can create new keys,
so what I'm going to do is, I'm going to create a new key, in ".ssh/id_rsa".
And this public key id "id_rsa.pub" will be uploaded to our instances,
and that way we will be able to log into our instances using our private key.
So, "id_rsa" is our private key.
These are public keys, public key goes in the instance, and we log in with the private key.
And, just one thing I want to do, before I'm going to do another kops command.
I'm just going to rename it to just kops, rather than having "kips-linux-amd64".
This is the kops command that I am going to execute.
And this kops command is not going to do anything yet, because it needs a lot of stuff,
before it's really going to execute the commands on AWS,
but this one is going to create one master at "t2.micro" and two nodes, also "t2.micro"
So, we have "kops create cluster".
Give it a name.
This needs to be the full DNS name of the cluster.
I have "kubernetes.newtech.academy", the one that I set up in Route 53.
I'm going to save the state in "s3", this is my "s3" bucket.
And I'm going to launch it in the "eu-west-1a" zone,  you're probably going to use another zone, "us-east-1a","us-west-1a", and so on.
node-count=2, and the node-size=t2.micro, and master-size=t2.micro, and the dns-zone=kubernetes.newtech.academy.
I am going to execute this.
And then you will be able to preview the changes that will be made to AWS.
So, it's going to make autoscaling groups for our nodes it's going to launch a master.
It's going to provision also ssd drives.
And then if you want to really launch this cluster, then we can just do this with "kops update cluster", and then the name with, "--yes".
And then it's going to launch, if you want to make changes first,
you can edit the cluster using, "kops edit cluster", and then the name, but because the state is on "s3"
you also have to specify the state. So then, the command will work and then you can still make some changes.
I am not going to make any changes at this point.
I'm just going to launch the cluster.
So, I am going to "kops update cluster", I am going to specify "--Yes".
And again I'll specify the "--state".
This will then launch your cluster.
It will take a couple of minutes and then I can try to run one of the examples.
So, now the cluster has been created and let's have a look what this means.
"/home [...]/config" for "kubernetes.newtech.academy" in this file. I am just going to "cat" this file--
And this is actually the certificate that we need and password to log in to our new cluster.
That's what kops configured already for us.
So, for instance, we have here to server "https://api.kubernetes.newtech.academy",
and that's what we will be able to use.
Let's see if the nodes are up.
So, "kubectl node", three nodes here with "ready" status.
One master is going to be to master, because it is on a  different IP range, and then two nodes.
Let's try to run something on this cluster. Let's try to run the same program the "hello-minikube", so that we can see if that also works.
So first we do, "kubectl run hello-minikube" with a image, and we specify a port, then it says, "deployment 'hello-minikube' created"
Typically on AWS when you want to access this service, we're going to put a load balancer in front like an ELB,
elastic load balancer, the server that AWS provides.
I'm going to explain this to you in the next lectures.
So, what I'm going to do now is, I'm going to do expose deployment just like we did with minikube.
And then, I would have to open a port. What port you able to see usin, "kubectl get service"?.
So, once this image is up, it gets assigned a port. "hello-minikube" is running, and this port is now exposed.
So, if we want to access it directly without a load balancer, we have to open this port in the firewall.
In the PC management console,
so if you go from "homescreen" to "VPC", and then you go to "Security Groups", then you see the "masters.kubernetes",
and this is the one we are going to edit.
and we are going to add another rule, this was the port, I am going to open this for everyone.
Let's see if this--
So, if you have a look at "ec2" services, these are instances that are running now.
If you take a look at route 53, then you see you have "api.kubernetes.newtech.academy", so we can use this to connect with our master node,
This is the only public IP that we can use now.
So, I'm going to try and connect to this hostname, on this port, and then you see, we get the end point of this application.
So, the application is running.
The port is now exposed.
Everything is working.
This was just a test, in the next coming lectures you will see, how to put this on a normal port,
on a normal HTTP port, for instance, using a load balancer.
But, for now, this is enough to test our cluster.
We can keep this cluster running or if you want to make sure that you're not paying for these instances
and these volumes here, you have some volumes here, you have some instances here.
If you will make sure you're not paying for them.
Then you can shut down your cluster again, and you can do it again using kops.
You can use kops, "kops delete cluster --name", DNS name.
It's going to then propose the resources it wants to delete and the these are all the resources.
If you agree with that.
You can specify "--yes".
And then it's going to delete all the resources, it's going to delete your cluster, VPC, everything that it's set up for you.
It's going to delete again.
So that was it.
If you had any issues during this process just use the Q&A, copy paste the error that you're getting, and I'm ready to help you.
Otherwise, if everything is working you, you can continue with the next lecture.