In this demo, I'll be running the first app behind a load balancer. I'm again going to log  into my vagrant box.
The same one I used to spin up my AWS Kubernetes cluster with kops
I have the Kubernetes course cloned right here.
If you haven't downloaded the course from git hub yet, have a look at the procedure document.
So, here I have two files I want to use
The first one is our "helloworld.yml", the pod, and I edited here the name.
So, it's still running on Port 3000, I just edited the name, "nodes-port"
Which you can then reuse in the service
So our service is going to be of type "LoadBalancer", which in our case is going to be an Elastic Load Balancer on AWS
It will be automatically created for us. Port is going to be 80, the standard HTTP
and the target port is going to be the "nodejs-port", then Kubernetes knows that it needs to go to this container
The protocol is TCP, the selector is going to refer to our apps, so we have app "helloworld".
it's going to be the service for the pod with the label app "helloworld".
I am going to run this "kubectl create -f" of the pod, and then of the service.
So, this takes some time, while is setting up, let's have a look in the AWS console.
Here on the main page and I go to "EC2" and we have now all one load balancer running.
So, this load balancer is internet facing, it's running on "Port 80", and it's going to refer to our three instances.
Those three instances will route the traffic to our pod.
That's why you'll be asked all three of them.
The ELB doesn't know exactly where the pod is running.
So it just add all three of them and every node will then redirect traffic to where the pod is.
Because, they know where the pod is.
There's a health check on the Port.
So, this is a node port and it's exposed on every node.
And that will be the port that is used by ELB.
So, the mapping is from "Port 80" on the ELB itself and it goes to the "Instance Port 32162" to the node itself.
And then on the node, it will redirect the traffic to the correct pod.
This ELB has a DNS name.
So, what you can actually do is if you go to "Route 53" these are routed records for Kubernetes zone.
I can create a new record and I can say, "helloworld.kubernetes"
and I can say this is an AWS for our load balancer. So, I can create this
and then I can actually use this to directly go to the load balancer and directly to my app.
If we go to "http://helloworld.kubernetes.newtech.academy"
You can see "Hello World!"
So, our "Route 53", "helloworld.kubernetes.newtech.academy" goes to our load balancer.
Our load balancer redirects the traffic from "Port 80" to one of those three notes on this instance port.
And then the traffic is redirected to pod,
which then gives, "Hello World!"
If you would go to the Security Groups, you would also see that
we have a new security group for our Load Balancer which is right here, ELB.
And then, if you go to nodes or even the Master you see that this one end is "2a"
We have all traffic open between our Kubernetes nodes and the Load Balancer.
So, the Load Balancer can access our Kubernetes cluster
So, that's it for this demo.
Now, we can actually create apps on Kubernetes that you can expose to the Internet
using the Elastic Load Balancer of Amazon.